A Inventory of the American Pictorial Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
American Pictorial Collection
1884-2001
XX765
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box, 68 envelopes, 1 oversize folder, 1 framed print (7.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs depicting various prominent personalities in the United States, American communists, and miscellaneous political, military and scientific scenes.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Communists--United States--Portraits.; United States--Pictorial works.
Container List
- 2 prints OF John Paul Jones' home in Scotland taken by Ben Berman, 1950. (File A)
- 1 print of American and Spanish delegates signing the treaty ending the Spanish-American War, 1898. (File mB)
  Autographed by the delegates.
- 4 negatives of Stanford University before the 1906 earthquake. (File C)
- 1 print of David S. Jordan. (File D)
- 1 print depicting Ray L. Wilbur presiding over the first telephone conversation between Stanford University and New York City, 1916. (File m*E)
- 1 print of Professor Edwin Francis Gay, autographed and presented to Ray L. Wilbur. (File F)
- 1 print of E.D. Adams' student assistants for the winter of 1921-1922. (File m*G)
- 1 autographed portrait of Putnam W. Eale, 1916. (File H)
- 1 print of Edna M. Hilton, member of the U.S. Food Administration and American Relief Administration, 1918. (File mI)
- 1 print of Private George H. Martin, Company A. 347th Machine Gun Battalion, killed in action on October 9, 1918. (File J)
- 1 print of General John J. Pershing, with Bishop Charles H. Brent, Chaplain General of the U.S. Army. (File K)
  Autographed.
- 7 prints depicting Red Cross offices during World War I. (File L)
- 4 prints (and 18 duplicates) depicting Woodrow Wilson on his trip to Europe, January 1919. (File M)
- 2 prints of Cordell Hull. (File N)
- 1 print of Calvin Coolidge with an unidentified woman. (File O)
- 2 prints of the Blacksmith shop of Jesse Hoover, father of President Herbert C. Hoover, taken at a ceremony on June 24, 1957. (File P)
  Governor of Iowa Herschel Loveless is shown looking at the tools inside the shop.
- 3 prints of Lou Henry Hoover and other taken at a girl scout camp, Camp Procter, Ohio, July 1922. (File Q)
- 1 print of L.H. Hoover as National President of the Girl Scouts, 1923. (File R)
- 1 print depicting the White House Reception of the 51st Annual Meeting of the American Library Assoc., 1929. (File m*S)
  Herbert Hoover is in the center of front row.
- 2 prints of the U.S.S. Arizona in Boston, 1931, and of President Herbert Hoover on the Arizona during a cruise to Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands, March 1931. (File T)
- 1 print of American clergyman Jenkin Lloyd Jones, director of the Abraham Lincoln Center, Chicago. (File mU)
- 1 print taken at a testimonial dinner to George Akerson given by the White House correspondents, New Willard, January 10, 1931, depicting George Akerson and participants. (File m*V)
- 344 prints and 60 negatives of alleged U.S. communists, 1930-1960. (File W-X)
- 1 print of the square-rigged sailing ship "Star of Alaska,", 1929. (File mY)
- 1 print depicting the launching of the "North Star" (U.S. Motor ship) at the Berg Shipbuilding Co., Seattle, Washington, January 8, 1932. (File mZ)
- 1 print depicting the U.S. Naval War College Staff and Class of 1923. (File AA)
  Chester W. Nimitz is standing in the center of the back row.
- 2 prints and 4 negatives depicting Robert L Eichelberger's service in the U.S. Army during the two world wars. (File AB)
- 1 print of admiral and diplomat Alan G. Kirk, 1888-1963. (File AC)
- 1 autographed print of Clarence Graff. (File AD)
- 1 print of F. Warner Karling. (File AE)
- 1 print of General Henry H. Arnold. (File AF)
- 1 print of General Omar Bradley. (File AG)
- 1 print of General James H. Doolittle. (File AH)
- 1 print of General Dwight D. Eisenhower. (File AI)
- 1 print of Lt. General John R. Hodge. (File AJ)
- 1 print of General Douglas A. MacArthur. (File AK)
- 1 print of General Harold M. McClelland (File AL)
- 1 print of General David M. Shoup (File AM)
- 1 print of Rear Admiral William S. Sims. (File AN)
- 1 print of General W. Bedell Smith. (File AO)
- 1 print of General Carl A. Spaatz. (File AP)
- 1 oversize postcard depicting the U.S.S. San Francisco Memorial in San Francisco, erected in 1950 in honor of the officers and men on board the cruiser San Francisco who were killed during the battle of Guadalcanal, November 1942. (File AQ)
- 3 prints distributed by the U.S. Navy, First Naval District, depicting the site of the Bethlehem Hingham Shipyards, Hingham, Mass., before and after construction of the shipyards, 1942-1943. (File AR)
- 1 print of the Pentagon Building, Washington, D.C., taken with the flag flying at half mast in honor of the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt, April 1945. (File AS)
- 2 prints of Russian interpreter Elanor Benetzka (one with General Lewis), taken in occupied Germany, 1946. (File AT)
- 5 prints distributed by the U.S. Army Signal Corps: 1 of general Douglas MacArthur and General Dwight Eisenhower; 1 of Donald Carpenter, Major General Thomas Green, and James Forrestal; 1 of General Hoyt Vandenberg, Admiral Louis Denfeld, and General Omar Bradley; 1 of Dr. Irene Kuehnel and others; 1 of two American soldiers and two Korean civilians. (File AU)
- 3 prints of U.S. Army Air Forces Airways and Air Communications Service. (File AV)
- 10 prints of tests of a V-2 rocket, taken at the U.S. Army Ordnance Proving Grounds, White Sands, New Mexico, 1946. (File AW)
- 6 prints of guided missiles and space vehicles, General Dynamics. (File AY)
- 5 prints of views of the moon taken by the United States Space Mission Apollo 8, 1968, and Apollo 10, 1969 (NASA). (File AZ)
- 3 prints showing contrast between television pictures taken with identical equipment except for the camera pick-up tubes. In one, the standard broadcast tube is used and, in the other, the new General Electric tube; in both, the subject is illuminated by moonlight only, 1960, General Electric Co. (File BA)
- 1 print of a magnetron, 1 print of a radarscope, Amperex Electronic Corporation. (File BB)
- 1 print of a cathode ray tube for use in high speed electronic printing process, Corning Glass Works. (File BC)
- 1 print of a weather balloon launching, U.S. Weather Bureau. (File BD)
- 1 print of weather detecting equipment, U.S. Department of Agriculture. (File BE)
- 3 oversize prints (apr. 10" x 30", rolled up) depicting the Atlantic Fleet at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, 1919, and the officers and crew of the U.S.S. Delaware at Guantanamo Bay, 1920. (Box 1)
- 1 print depicting a labor rally, presumably held in Detroit, April 1947. (File mBF)
- 1 print depicting a painting of Herbert Hoover in a motor boat (hung in the Angler's Club on Key Largo, Florida) (File BG)
- 61 negatives, 1918, depicting U.S. Army YMCA camp Beauregard in Louisiana. (File BH)
- 2 prints of Herbert C. Hoover, including one at Park Ridge, 1928; and 1 print of the bust of John C. Branner, on display in the Hoover Tower Lobby. (File BI)
- Two copies and one negative of a print depicting the members of Company "E" 162nd U.S. Infantry, acting as guard of honor for President Wilson in London, 28 December 1918. (File *mBJ)
- 2 prints depicting Hoover Dam. (File mBK)
- 2 prints depicting the former home of Theodore Hoover, brother of Herbert Hoover, in Bodie, California, now a ghost twon, Bodie State Park, 1990. (File BL)
- 1 print depicting Emma Goldman writing at her desk, ca. 1910. (File mBM)
- 1 print n.d., depicting Cyrus R. Vance when Secretary of the Army. (File BN)
- 1 print depicting a 10-yeard old Herbert Hoover standing in front of the Friends Pacific Academy in Newberg, Oregon, 1884. (File BO)
- 1 oversize print of Herbert Hoover with the Washington State College Football team at the White House, 1930. (File mBP*)
  (On art racks.)
- 1 oversize print of Joseph Swain. (File mBQ)
- 1 print of Herbert Hoover, General Mark Clark, John Erhardt and Chancellor Leopold Figl in Vienna, 1946. (File BR)
- 1 folder of slides of a demonstration by Women Strike for peach in Washington D.C., 1964. (Box 2)
  1 print of John Philip Sousa band at Hoover House, Stanford University, 1928.